Ricky, Ching Ping Leung

415-609-1344

ricxx0320@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricky-leung-826a7713a/

https://github.com/ricky0320

Portfolio (In-progress): https://ricky0320.github.io/my-portfolio/

Skills:

Software/OS/Configurations

Windows 7, 10 upgrades/deployment | imaging (SCCM/Ghost) | OS troubleshoot/maintenance | Office365 | Outlook | Remote Support | TCP/IP/DHCP/domain setup | VPN | Laptops

Programming

Front-end:

JavaScript | Git | APIs | HTML | CSS | Python | JQuery | Node.JS | React

Back-end:

Express.JS | SQL | Authentication | MERN | Model-View-Controller(MVC) | Heroku | Insomnia

Network/Admin tools

Active Directory | Two-Factor Authentication (RSA) | ServiceNow Ticketing | Jarvis CRM | SCCM | RDP

Hardware

Peripherals/Parts replacement, upgrades | Full computer deployment | A/V conference room setup| Cisco VOIP phones

MDM/Mobile Support

Work Space One AirWatch | (50% Android, 50% IOS) | VPN (AnyConnect) | Apps troubleshooting | Peripherals/Device connectivity

Personality

Great customer service and team player. Quick learner. Have experience with MacOSX Sierra/HighSierra/Catilina and Windows 7,10. In-progress learning in JavaScript, APIs, Git, HTML/CSS, Python, SQL, JQuery, NodeJS. Like evaluating and solving new complex issues and share results with team for future use. Bi-lingual, fluent in Cantonese, able to read/type/write Chinese. Pet friendly. Willing to learn. Just graduated from UC Berkeley's coding bootcamp for full stack web development.

Experience:

San Francisco Environment Department(ENV) IT Operation Support Administrator III

1/4/2021 - present

- Remote support with RDP/SCCM/UltraVNC remote tools.
- Windows/MacOSX and Android/IOS support and configuration.
- O365 Admin manage license/user groups/shared mailbox/mailbox delegations.
- SCCM imaging OS, software packaging, task sequence deployment, run test.
- Data migration with Sharepoint migration tool. Drive mapping.
- Set up/remove users, edit group members, reset password in Active Directory.
- Software updates, hardware upgrade/replacement (Memory, M.2/SSD/HDD...)

- Troubleshoot VPN connection (Cisco AnyConnect), remote connection, application error, track problems from Trace log, analyze and resolve.
- Keep track and resolve tickets with ServiceNow ticketing system
- Monitor computer/network status and visualize issues with Kace, Tanium and Splunk.
- Create templates, screenshot guides and tutorials for end users for common and simple issue fix.
- Configure/check Windows settings through Computer Management, configuration manager, Group policy, registry and command prompt/terminal.
- Manage inventory and equipment storage for replacement or rollout.

San Francisco Police Department(SFPD) IT Operation Support Administrator

1/14/2019 - 1/14/2020

- Reset user and Email password and add group member and create/remove users through Active Directory.
- Resolve tickets with ServiceNow ticketing system.
- Remote into user's computers and troubleshoot problem. (Remote Desktop Connection/Ultra VNC). Updates software and configure Windows setting and troubleshoot Office365. (Outlook, Excel)
- Upgrade/image Windows 7 to 10 to latest build. (Ghost/SCCM)
- Setup conference room/cisco VOIP phones for meeting.
- Travel to multiple stations to perform maintenance and updates. Provide configuration and hardware upgrades when requested. Replace computers or certain parts upon requests. Update group policies.
- Telecom management with VMware Workspace One Airwatch. Push out missing apps. Lock/Unlock user's phone through cloud platform and manage user's device license by MDM.
- Deploy new phones (Android) to all SFPD Stations. Flash, setup, configure and troubleshoot mobile devices (Android) in a 2500+ phones rollout project.
- Worked directly with AT&T and Samsung manger in phone projects.
- Setup/Troubleshoot network TCP/IP/DHCP and configure IP settings and domain, workgroup and other connectivity issue. Server room data cable tracing/connecting.

Linkedin, Dropbox, Salesforce, Amazon(outsourced by EMR CPR Enterprise IT) IT Consultant 01/2017- 10/2018

- Run projects and manage a team of 5-25 to setup and relocate workstations and provide excellent customer service in a quick pace.
- Real-time update project and report to Project Manager with Jarvis CRM business tools.(Private ticketing system)
- Follow up support to clients for ongoing questions and problems and provide the best solutions. Keep clients updated of the process and make sure clients are satisfied with the work. Perform walkthrough with clients to make sure jobs are done before leaving.
- Provide the best suggestions and solutions for clients on all sort of computer problems including software updates and

hardware upgrades/replacement.

- Report to project manager after each job and obtain feedbacks for further improvement.
- Setup printer/copiers (MFP) and configure network and shared settings

EMR CPR Enterprise IT(MSP)

Project Lead 01/2017- 10/2018

- Contact clients and vendors for individual projects.
- Analyze and control budget on each projects, support directly with the CEO.
- Provide training to junior/entry level technicians.
- Maintain office computers at healthy status. Prepare inventory for each project with Google Docs.

Recology, San Francisco, CA Helpdesk Assistant (Part time)

08/2017- 10/2017

- Assist manager with windows upgrade project
- Change BIOs setting and password
- Configure firewall, network setting and TCP/IP destination
- Assist with Windows system recovery and data migration. Operate hard disk defragment to check disk health and prepare upgrades to Windows 10.
- Troubleshoot users' computers, make sure their computers have the best performance. Change display settings and desktop interface for new monitors/equipment.

Kam Wan Key, San Francisco, CA IT Consultant

02/2016-02/2017

- Handle all computer and mobile devices issues including network diagnostic, system error, hardware and software. Setup and configure modem and router, firewall, IP and ports. Provide step by step guidelines on basic usage of computers for new computer users.
- Data migration between mobile device and computers/laptops. (Android and IOS)
- Router setting (TCPIP/DHCP/Port forwarding). Make sure all mobile devices have network access.
- Provide training/guides to users by screenshots and Word.
- Setup and configure security cameras, help monitoring cameras in office hours.
- Prepare inventory and invoice with Excel and Google Docs.

Geary Chiropractic Clinic, San Francisco, CA

IT Consultant 07/2012- 07/2013

- Troubleshoot all computer issues, software and network problem. Give advice for hardware and equipment upgrade.
- Prepare inventory and manage data backup.
- Purchase necessary equipment.
- Personal mobile devices setup and connection/troubleshooting.
- Contact vendor for printer maintenance and warranty when needed.

Education:

University of California, Riverside B.S. in Business Administration

05/2012

Certification:

Coursera's Machine Learning Certification Stanford University

09/2020

(https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/VNYXBMEDJA8F?utm_source= In&utm_medium=certificate&utm_content=cert_image&utm_campaign=sharing_cta&utm_product=course)

UC Berkeley Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

03/2022